<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
     <string-array name="symps">
         <item name="s0">Vomiting, diarrhea, hyperactivity, muscle twitching, labored breathing. Symptoms will be present within first few hours after consumption.</item>
         <item name="s1">Weakness(lethargy), vomiting, diarrhea, difficulty breathing, bloddy urine, and increased heart rate. Presence of symptoms may depend on amount consumed and may show over time</item>
         <item name="s2">Vomiting, diarrhea, excessive thirst, excessive urination and or weakness(lethargy). Symptoms may be present within a few hours after consumption.</item>
         <item name="s3">Hyperactivity, restlessness, vomiting, elevated heart rate, elevated blood pressure, hyperthermia, siezures, and collapse. Symptoms are present between 1 and 2 hours after consumption.</item>
         <item name="s4">Ataxia(walking wobbly), depression, vomiting, muscle tremors, hyperthermia, and elevated heart rate. Symptoms are usually present within 12 hours of ingestion.</item>
         <item name="s5">Excessive drooling, vomiting, diarrhea, abdominal pain, lethargy, siezures, and abnormal heart rate. Symptoms typically occur within the first few hours after consumption.</item>
         <item name="s6">Excessive drooling, vomiting, diarrhea, bloody diarrhea, respiratory failure, and siezures. Symptoms may be apparent 1 to 2 hours after consumption.</item>
         <item name="s7">Excessive drooling, nausea, vomiting, abnormal heart rate, lethargy, dilated pupils, and siezures. Symptoms typically occur within 2 hours after consumption.</item>
         <item name="s8">Vomiting, diarrhea, drooling, lethargy, disorientation, siezures and difficulty breathing. Symptoms may occur within 2 hours after consumption.</item>
         <item name="s9">Hyper salivating, vomiting, diarrhea, frequent urination, elevated heart rate, and elevated respiratory rate. Symptoms often are seen within 1 or 2 hours after consumption.</item>
         <item name="s10">Drunken behavior(wobbly or uncoordinated movement), nausea, excessive urination, rapid heart rate, lethargy, siezures, and euphoria.</item>
         <item name="s11">Loss of appetite, impared movement, paralysis of hind limbs, muslce tremors, siezures, and depression of the nervous system. Symptoms may occur within 1 to 7 days of consumption.</item>
         <item name="s12">Twitching, excessive drooling, high fever, increased heart rate, vomiting, siezures, and respiratory failure. Symptoms occur quickly when ingested, often within the first hour.</item>
        
     </string-array>
         
     <string-array name="descr">
         <item name="d0">Chocolate is deadly due to the presence of theobromine, a natural stimulant found in the cocoa bean. Theobromine affects the central nervous system as well as the heart itself. Because dark chocolate has higher amounts of cocoa than milk or lighter chocolate, dark chocolate contains higher levels of theobromine and is therfore much more toxic. Consult your vet as soon as possible.</item>
         <item name="d1">Onions contain a substance called thiosulphate which dogs and cats are unable to properly digest. Thiosulphate damages the hemoglobin in canine red cells that form clumps weakening the cell membrane. The result at a high level of red blood cell damage is anemia and may eave the body starving for oxygen. Consult your vet as soon as possible.</item>
         <item name="d2">Currently it is not absolutely known what part of the grape is toxic and therfore any amount consumed should be a cause for conern. Because raisons are dried and more concentrated than grapes, it is assumed that the toxic component within grapes is also at a higher concentration within raisons. Consult your vet as soon as possible. Especially if a large amount is consumed.</item>
         <item name="d3">Dogs are much more sensitive to the effects of coffee than people are. Although small amounts of coffee or soda usually isn\'t a problem the ingestion of small amount of coffee grain or tea bags can easily cause severe smptoms and even be fatal. Consult your vet especially if coffee frain or tea bags are consumed.</item>
         <item name="d4">SImilarly to grapes, the component of macadamia nuts that cause toxicity is unknown. Amount consumed may vary between dogs in relation to the level of toxicity, although a small amount is still considered potentially dangerous due to the unknown cause for the reaction. The most common cases of toxicity include chocolate foods that contain macadamia nuts. Consult your vet.</item>
         <item name="d5">The toxic principle of the azalea interferes with normal skeletal muscle, the heart and nerve function resulting in situations where a pet may have leg paralysis, loss of coordination or even comatose. Often if the pet becomes comatose the possibilty of the situation becoming fatal is increased. Consult your vet immediately if consumed.</item>
         <item name="d6">There are two types of crocus plants. One type grows in the spring while the other grows during the autumn season. The more severe symptoms include severe gastrointestinal signs as well as kidney damage, central nervous system signs, and respiratory failure usually from the autumn crocus. The spring crocus can give the same results with larger amounts. Consult your vet immediately.</item>
         <item name="d7">Foxglove contains naturally occuring poisons that affect the heart. These poisons directly interfere with the electrolyte balance of the heart. Although poisonous for dogs and other small animals, foxgloves can be poisonous to humans as well. Consult your vet immediately.</item>
         <item name="d8">Often associated with the winter holidays, juniper is often one of the items pets get into during the winter holidays. Although having a lower level of toxicity, do not dismiss if pet consumes large amount or is a small dog and eats any amount. Observe your dog for the first few hours after consumption. If necessary consult your vet.</item>
         <item name="d9">Mistletoe is not just another plant associated with the winter holidays. Probably the most common around Christmas time, this plants toxicity is mostly found within the berries. Usually a large amount is needed for higher levels of toxicity but may cause GI upset in small amounts as well. Consult your vet if listed symptoms begins after consumption.</item>
         <item name="d10">Because Antifreeze symptoms are often faint within the first 3 to 8 hours after consumption, it is often difficult to diagnose quickly. By the time symptoms begin, irreversible damage to the kidneys may have occurred. This is partially what makes this toxicity so dangerous. Induce vomiting if possible and take to the vet hospital immediately for observation if uncertain of antifreeze consumption.</item>
         <item name="d11">Because rat poison takes longer to show symptoms, the level of danger increases. This toxin affects blood clotting and may result in anemia and edema within the body. Rat poison must be taken seriously as this can fatal. Induce vomiting as soon as possible and take to vet hospital as soon as possible.</item>
         <item name="d12">Snail bait affects the nervous system. Small amounts of snail bait may become fatal, therefore it is recommmended to take to the vet hospital immediately to induce vomiting, supportive treatment, and observation as ingestion may become fatal within only a few hours. Every minute counts.</item>
         
      </string-array>
</resources>